<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-10T14:51:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Cookbook</title><subtitle>This is a collection of my favorite recipes, taken and adapted from friends, family, and various places across the internet.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Papi chulo sauce</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/recipes/sauces/papi-chulo-sauce.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Papi chulo sauce" /><published>2021-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/recipes/sauces/papi-chulo-sauce</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/recipes/sauces/papi-chulo-sauce.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 bunches cilantro with stems (washed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-2 serrano peppers (with seeds)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 jalapeño peppers (with seeds)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cloves garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons rice vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons mustard (see note)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;juice of 4 limes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;juice of half lemon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;juice of 1 orange&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cups olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tablespoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tablespoon pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In a food processor or blender combine everything except one bunch of cilantro.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blend until everything is mixed and incorporated. Taste and add additional
peppers for heat or salt and pepper to taste&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add the 2nd bunch of cilantro and pulse until cilantro is chopped.  Store in
an airtight container in the refrigerator. Can keep up to 3 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes--tips&quot;&gt;Notes &amp;amp; tips&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This recipe varies quite a bit depending on the mustard you use. I prefer a
mustard that is slightly sweet and spicy — Bone Suckin’ Mustard is my go to
if you can find it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Kumbier</name></author><category term="sauces" /><summary type="html">Ingredients 2 bunches cilantro with stems (washed) 1-2 serrano peppers (with seeds) 1 jalapeño peppers (with seeds) 4 cloves garlic 2 teaspoons rice vinegar 3 tablespoons mustard (see note) juice of 4 limes juice of half lemon juice of 1 orange 1/2 cups olive oil 1 tablespoon sugar 1/2 tablespoon salt 1/2 tablespoon pepper Directions In a food processor or blender combine everything except one bunch of cilantro. Blend until everything is mixed and incorporated. Taste and add additional peppers for heat or salt and pepper to taste Add the 2nd bunch of cilantro and pulse until cilantro is chopped. Store in an airtight container in the refrigerator. Can keep up to 3 weeks. Notes &amp;amp; tips This recipe varies quite a bit depending on the mustard you use. I prefer a mustard that is slightly sweet and spicy — Bone Suckin’ Mustard is my go to if you can find it!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/papi-chulo-sauce.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/papi-chulo-sauce.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pie crust</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/recipes/doughs/pie-crust.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pie crust" /><published>2021-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/recipes/doughs/pie-crust</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/recipes/doughs/pie-crust.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 ounces all-purpose flour, such as King Arthur (1 2/3 cups; 225g), plus more for dusting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 ounce sugar (1 tablespoon; 15g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon (4g) Diamond Crystal kosher salt; for table salt, use half as much by volume or use the same weight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 ounces unsalted, American-style butter, straight from the fridge (2 sticks; 225g), cold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 ounces cold tap water (1/2 cup; 115g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 teaspoon (0.5g) Diamond Crystal kosher salt; for table salt, use half as much by volume or use the same weight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the Dough:&lt;/strong&gt; Whisk flour, sugar, and salt together in a medium bowl.
Cut butter into cubes no smaller than 1/2 inch, and toss with flour mixture
to break up the pieces. With your fingertips, smash each cube flat—that’s it! No
rubbing or cutting. Stir in water, then knead dough against sides of the bowl
until flour has just barely incorporated. Dough temperature should register
between 65 and 70°F (18 and 21°C); if not, refrigerate briefly before rolling
and folding (see note).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make the Layers:&lt;/strong&gt; On a generously floured work surface, roll dough into a
roughly 10- by 15-inch rectangle. Fold the 10-inch sides to the center, then
close the newly formed packet like a book. Fold in half once more, bringing the
short sides together to create a thick block. Divide in half with a sharp knife
or bench scraper. Dough temperature should still be somewhere between 65 and
70°F (18 and 21°C); if not, refrigerate briefly before proceeding&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using as much flour as needed, roll one piece into a 14-inch circle; this
size allows ample room to line pie plate, with enough overhang to form a
generous border. At smaller sizes, dough will fall short, making it difficult to
shape edges, and thicker dough will not crisp as intended. Transfer to 9-inch
pie plate; dough should be easy to handle, and will not require any special
procedures to move. Dust off excess flour with a pastry brush, using it to
nestle dough into corners of pan. With scissors or kitchen shears, trim edge so
that it overhangs by 1 1/4 inches. For solid top crust, roll remaining dough as
before; for lattice-top pie, roll into a 9- by 15-inch rectangle instead.
Transfer to a baking sheet or parchment-lined cutting board.  (The parchment
will prevent dough from absorbing any savory odors from the board.) Wrap both
portions in plastic and refrigerate at least 2 hours and up to overnight. Use as
directed in your favorite recipe; after filling pie and sealing crusts together,
refrigerate 30 minutes before baking.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recipe is largely adapted from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seriouseats.com/best-blueberry-pie-dessert-recipe&quot;&gt;serious
eats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Kumbier</name></author><category term="doughs" /><summary type="html">Ingredients 8 ounces all-purpose flour, such as King Arthur (1 2/3 cups; 225g), plus more for dusting 1/2 ounce sugar (1 tablespoon; 15g) 1 teaspoon (4g) Diamond Crystal kosher salt; for table salt, use half as much by volume or use the same weight 8 ounces unsalted, American-style butter, straight from the fridge (2 sticks; 225g), cold 4 ounces cold tap water (1/2 cup; 115g) 1/8 teaspoon (0.5g) Diamond Crystal kosher salt; for table salt, use half as much by volume or use the same weight Directions For the Dough: Whisk flour, sugar, and salt together in a medium bowl. Cut butter into cubes no smaller than 1/2 inch, and toss with flour mixture to break up the pieces. With your fingertips, smash each cube flat—that’s it! No rubbing or cutting. Stir in water, then knead dough against sides of the bowl until flour has just barely incorporated. Dough temperature should register between 65 and 70°F (18 and 21°C); if not, refrigerate briefly before rolling and folding (see note). Make the Layers: On a generously floured work surface, roll dough into a roughly 10- by 15-inch rectangle. Fold the 10-inch sides to the center, then close the newly formed packet like a book. Fold in half once more, bringing the short sides together to create a thick block. Divide in half with a sharp knife or bench scraper. Dough temperature should still be somewhere between 65 and 70°F (18 and 21°C); if not, refrigerate briefly before proceeding Using as much flour as needed, roll one piece into a 14-inch circle; this size allows ample room to line pie plate, with enough overhang to form a generous border. At smaller sizes, dough will fall short, making it difficult to shape edges, and thicker dough will not crisp as intended. Transfer to 9-inch pie plate; dough should be easy to handle, and will not require any special procedures to move. Dust off excess flour with a pastry brush, using it to nestle dough into corners of pan. With scissors or kitchen shears, trim edge so that it overhangs by 1 1/4 inches. For solid top crust, roll remaining dough as before; for lattice-top pie, roll into a 9- by 15-inch rectangle instead. Transfer to a baking sheet or parchment-lined cutting board. (The parchment will prevent dough from absorbing any savory odors from the board.) Wrap both portions in plastic and refrigerate at least 2 hours and up to overnight. Use as directed in your favorite recipe; after filling pie and sealing crusts together, refrigerate 30 minutes before baking. Resources This recipe is largely adapted from serious eats.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/pie-crust.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/pie-crust.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pork belly tacos</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/recipes/mains/pork-pelly-tacos.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pork belly tacos" /><published>2021-10-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/recipes/mains/pork-pelly-tacos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/recipes/mains/pork-pelly-tacos.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pork-belly&quot;&gt;Pork belly&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound pork belly, skin removed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup coconut soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;juice from 1 lime&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup coconut vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup sriracha&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons honey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 teaspoon fish sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pineapple-salsa&quot;&gt;Pineapple salsa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup diced pineapple&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 purple cabbage, thinly sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large carrot, julienned&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;small handful of cilantro, roughly chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;small handful of mint, roughly chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;juice of 1/2 lime&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sriracha-mayo&quot;&gt;Sriracha mayo:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup avocado oil mayo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup sriracha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-the-tacos&quot;&gt;For the tacos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4–6 cassava tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cilantro, for garnish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whisk the pork belly sauce ingredients together. Divide in half and set half
of it in a container for later. Pour the other half of the marinade into a
ziplock bag then add pork belly, cover and place in the fridge overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The next day, remove pork belly from the marinade (discard marinade) and pay
dry.  Preheat oven to 450 degrees F. Line a baking sheet with foil and place
a wire rack on top. Place pork belly fat side up on the wire rack. Put in the
oven to bake for 30 minutes then turn oven down to 225 degrees F and cook for 1
hour. (1 hour per pound of pork belly) Once cooked, remove and let rest for 5-10
minutes before slicing into small bite size pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the pork belly has about 15 minutes left in the oven, prepare the
pineapple salsa. Add all ingredients in a bowl to combine and set aside.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whisk together the sriracha mayo and set aside.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using the marinade that you placed in a container the night before, pour it
into a large skillet over medium heat. Bring to boil and let reduce until the
mixture thickens and coats the back of a spoon, about 8-10 minutes. Once
thickened, toss pork belly in the sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Heat tortillas over an open flame on our stovetop or in a pan, then add pork
belly, pineapple salsa, and sriracha mayo on top of all of it!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Kumbier</name></author><category term="mains" /><summary type="html">Ingredients Pork belly 1 pound pork belly, skin removed 1/2 cup coconut soy sauce juice from 1 lime 1/2 cup coconut vinegar 1/4 cup sriracha 2 tablespoons honey 2 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon garlic powder 1/4 teaspoon fish sauce Pineapple salsa 1 cup diced pineapple 1/4 purple cabbage, thinly sliced 1 large carrot, julienned small handful of cilantro, roughly chopped small handful of mint, roughly chopped juice of 1/2 lime pinch of salt Sriracha mayo: 1/2 cup avocado oil mayo 1/4 cup sriracha For the tacos 4–6 cassava tortillas cilantro, for garnish Directions Whisk the pork belly sauce ingredients together. Divide in half and set half of it in a container for later. Pour the other half of the marinade into a ziplock bag then add pork belly, cover and place in the fridge overnight. The next day, remove pork belly from the marinade (discard marinade) and pay dry. Preheat oven to 450 degrees F. Line a baking sheet with foil and place a wire rack on top. Place pork belly fat side up on the wire rack. Put in the oven to bake for 30 minutes then turn oven down to 225 degrees F and cook for 1 hour. (1 hour per pound of pork belly) Once cooked, remove and let rest for 5-10 minutes before slicing into small bite size pieces. When the pork belly has about 15 minutes left in the oven, prepare the pineapple salsa. Add all ingredients in a bowl to combine and set aside. Whisk together the sriracha mayo and set aside. Using the marinade that you placed in a container the night before, pour it into a large skillet over medium heat. Bring to boil and let reduce until the mixture thickens and coats the back of a spoon, about 8-10 minutes. Once thickened, toss pork belly in the sauce. Heat tortillas over an open flame on our stovetop or in a pan, then add pork belly, pineapple salsa, and sriracha mayo on top of all of it!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/pork-belly-tacos.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/pork-belly-tacos.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Blueberry orange pie</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/recipes/desserts/blueberry-orange-pie.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blueberry orange pie" /><published>2021-10-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/recipes/desserts/blueberry-orange-pie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/recipes/desserts/blueberry-orange-pie.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;filling&quot;&gt;Filling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;20 ounces fresh blueberries (3 1/4 cups; 565g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 ounces wild blueberries (2 cups; 225g), fresh or frozen (see note)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ounce fresh juice from 1 orange (2 tablespoons; 30g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ounce orange zest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7 ounces sugar (1 cup; 195g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons vanilla&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon (2g) Diamond Crystal kosher salt; for table salt, use half as much by volume or use the same weight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 ounces tapioca starch (1/3 cup plus 1 teaspoon; 40g), such as Bob’s Red Mill (see note)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/recipes/doughs/pie-crust.html&quot;&gt;Pie Dough&lt;/a&gt;, rolled and chilled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;egg-wash-optional&quot;&gt;Egg Wash (optional):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large egg yolk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 ounce heavy cream (1 tablespoon; 15g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 teaspoon (0.5g) Diamond Crystal kosher salt; for table salt, use half as much by volume or use the same weight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the Filling:&lt;/strong&gt; Toss regular and wild blueberries, orange juice, sugar, salt,
vanilla, and tapioca starch in a large bowl, folding with a
flexible spatula until well combined. Scrape into prepared pie shell and top
with remaining dough, using a solid sheet, cutouts, or a lattice-top design.
(Check out my tutorial here.) Trim away excess dough and refrigerate to ensure
top crust is completely chilled, about 30 minutes. Meanwhile, adjust oven rack
to lower-middle position and preheat to 400°F (200°C).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the Egg Wash (if using):&lt;/strong&gt; Whisk egg, egg yolk, cream, and salt in a
small bowl. Brush over chilled top crust in a thin, even layer. This will
give the crust a glossy, golden sheen, but it is not necessary in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Place chilled pie on a parchment-lined half-sheet pan. Bake until crust is
golden, about 1 hour, then loosely cover with tented foil. (Alternatively, an
empty baking sheet can be placed on the topmost rack of the oven to serve as a
shield.) Continue baking until filling is bubbling even in the very center of
the pie, about 15 minutes longer. If crust completely covers filling, bake until
pie reaches an internal temperature of 213°F (101°C) on a digital thermometer.
The time can vary considerably depending on the thickness and type of pie plate,
the amount of top crust, how long the pie was refrigerated, et cetera.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To Serve: Cool pie until no warmer than 85°F (29°C) on a digital thermometer,
about 3 hours depending on the type of pie plate (at higher temperatures,
filling will be runny and thin). Slice into wedges with a sharp knife, pressing
firmly against bottom and sides of pie plate to ensure the bottom crust is
completely cut. If you like, serve with Lemon Chantilly. Wrapped in foil,
leftovers will keep up to 3 days at room temperature; warm 10 minutes in a 350°F
(180°C) oven to revive crust before serving.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recipe is largely adapted from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seriouseats.com/best-blueberry-pie-dessert-recipe&quot;&gt;serious
eats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Kumbier</name></author><category term="desserts" /><summary type="html">Ingredients Filling 20 ounces fresh blueberries (3 1/4 cups; 565g) 8 ounces wild blueberries (2 cups; 225g), fresh or frozen (see note) 1 ounce fresh juice from 1 orange (2 tablespoons; 30g) 1 ounce orange zest 7 ounces sugar (1 cup; 195g) 2 teaspoons vanilla 1/2 teaspoon (2g) Diamond Crystal kosher salt; for table salt, use half as much by volume or use the same weight 1 1/2 ounces tapioca starch (1/3 cup plus 1 teaspoon; 40g), such as Bob’s Red Mill (see note) Pie Dough, rolled and chilled. Egg Wash (optional): 1 large egg 1 large egg yolk 1/2 ounce heavy cream (1 tablespoon; 15g) 1/8 teaspoon (0.5g) Diamond Crystal kosher salt; for table salt, use half as much by volume or use the same weight Directions For the Filling: Toss regular and wild blueberries, orange juice, sugar, salt, vanilla, and tapioca starch in a large bowl, folding with a flexible spatula until well combined. Scrape into prepared pie shell and top with remaining dough, using a solid sheet, cutouts, or a lattice-top design. (Check out my tutorial here.) Trim away excess dough and refrigerate to ensure top crust is completely chilled, about 30 minutes. Meanwhile, adjust oven rack to lower-middle position and preheat to 400°F (200°C). For the Egg Wash (if using): Whisk egg, egg yolk, cream, and salt in a small bowl. Brush over chilled top crust in a thin, even layer. This will give the crust a glossy, golden sheen, but it is not necessary in any way. Place chilled pie on a parchment-lined half-sheet pan. Bake until crust is golden, about 1 hour, then loosely cover with tented foil. (Alternatively, an empty baking sheet can be placed on the topmost rack of the oven to serve as a shield.) Continue baking until filling is bubbling even in the very center of the pie, about 15 minutes longer. If crust completely covers filling, bake until pie reaches an internal temperature of 213°F (101°C) on a digital thermometer. The time can vary considerably depending on the thickness and type of pie plate, the amount of top crust, how long the pie was refrigerated, et cetera. To Serve: Cool pie until no warmer than 85°F (29°C) on a digital thermometer, about 3 hours depending on the type of pie plate (at higher temperatures, filling will be runny and thin). Slice into wedges with a sharp knife, pressing firmly against bottom and sides of pie plate to ensure the bottom crust is completely cut. If you like, serve with Lemon Chantilly. Wrapped in foil, leftovers will keep up to 3 days at room temperature; warm 10 minutes in a 350°F (180°C) oven to revive crust before serving. Resources This recipe is largely adapted from serious eats.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/blueberry-orange-pie.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/blueberry-orange-pie.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Detroit style pizza</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/recipes/mains/detroit-style-pizza.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Detroit style pizza" /><published>2021-10-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/recipes/mains/detroit-style-pizza</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/recipes/mains/detroit-style-pizza.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dough&quot;&gt;Dough:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;300g bread flour (10.5 ounces; about 2 generous cups)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5g instant yeast (0.15 ounce; about 1 teaspoon), such as SAF Instant Yeast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9g salt (0.3 ounce; about 1 1/2 teaspoons table salt or 1 tablespoon Diamond Crystal kosher salt)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;220g water (7.75 ounces; about 1 cup minus 1 1/2 teaspoons)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extra-virgin olive oil, as needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sauce&quot;&gt;Sauce:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons (30ml) extra-virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 medium cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons (about 5g) dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dash red pepper flakes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 (28-ounce; 800g) can high-quality crushed tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon (about 6g) granulated garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon (about 6g) granulated onion powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon (about 15g) sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kosher salt, to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finish&quot;&gt;Finish:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12 ounces (340g) cheese, cut into 1/2-inch cubes (see note)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toppings (see note)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Combine flour, yeast, and salt in the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with a
dough hook attachment. Stir to combine, then add water. Mix on low speed
until dough comes together into a rough ball, then shut off mixer and let rest
for 10 minutes. Continue mixing at medium-low speed until dough forms a smooth,
silky ball, about 10 minutes longer. (It should stick to the bottom of the bowl
as it kneads rather than riding around the edges.) Remove dough hook, form dough
into a tight ball, set in the bottom of the mixer bowl, cover tightly with
plastic wrap, and set aside in a warm place until dough has roughly doubled in
volume, about 2 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pour a couple tablespoons olive oil in the bottom of a Detroit-style anodized
aluminum pan or two 8- by 8-inch cake pans. (Split dough in half if using
cake pans.) Transfer dough to pan(s) and turn to coat in oil. Press down on
dough and spread it toward the edges. You won’t be able to get it all the way to
the edges; this is okay. Spread it as much as you can without tearing, then
cover tightly in plastic and set aside for 30 minutes to allow dough to relax.
Return to dough and stretch it out again. It should be able to reach the edges
this time. If not, let it rest a little more and try again. To get the dough to
stay in the corners, stretch it up beyond the corners so that it pulls back into
place. Once dough is stretched, cover again and set aside while you make the
sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the Sauce: Adjust oven rack to lowest position and preheat oven to 550°F
(290°C), or as close to it as your oven gets. Heat 2 tablespoons (30ml) olive
oil in a medium saucepan over medium heat until shimmering. Add minced garlic,
oregano, and pepper flakes and cook, stirring, until fragrant, about 30 seconds.
Add tomatoes, garlic powder, onion powder, and sugar. Bring to a simmer and cook
until reduced to about 3 cups, about 30 minutes. Season to taste with salt.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To Form the Pizza: Press down on dough with your fingertips to remove any
large air bubbles. Lay half of pepperoni (if using) evenly over face of
dough. Top with cheese, spreading it evenly all the way to the very edges of the
pan, then add remaining pepperoni. Spoon sauce over surface in 3 even rows. (You
will need only about half the sauce—save the rest for another pizza.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Transfer to oven and bake until edges are black and bubbly and exposed cheese
on top is starting to lightly brown, 12 to 15 minutes. Transfer to a trivet
or folded kitchen towel on countertop.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Run a thin metal spatula all the way around the edges of the pan to loosen
the pizza. Carefully lift it out and slide it onto a cutting board. Cut pizza
and serve.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes--tips&quot;&gt;Notes &amp;amp; tips&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The original recipe calls for brick cheese. I’ve had trouble finding this and
use a combination of low-moisture mozzarella, mild cheddar, parmesean, and
asiago.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My preferred toppings are caramelized onion and mushroom.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For best results, use a Detroit-style anodized aluminum pan. If you can’t get
your hands on that kind of pan, you can split the recipe into two square 8-
by 8-inch cake pans.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recipe is taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seriouseats.com/detroit-style-pizza-recipe&quot;&gt;serious
eats&lt;/a&gt; with essentially
no changes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Kumbier</name></author><category term="mains" /><summary type="html">Ingredients Dough: 300g bread flour (10.5 ounces; about 2 generous cups) 5g instant yeast (0.15 ounce; about 1 teaspoon), such as SAF Instant Yeast 9g salt (0.3 ounce; about 1 1/2 teaspoons table salt or 1 tablespoon Diamond Crystal kosher salt) 220g water (7.75 ounces; about 1 cup minus 1 1/2 teaspoons) Extra-virgin olive oil, as needed Sauce: 2 tablespoons (30ml) extra-virgin olive oil 3 medium cloves garlic, minced 2 teaspoons (about 5g) dried oregano Dash red pepper flakes 1 (28-ounce; 800g) can high-quality crushed tomatoes 1 teaspoon (about 6g) granulated garlic powder 1 teaspoon (about 6g) granulated onion powder 1 tablespoon (about 15g) sugar Kosher salt, to taste Finish: 12 ounces (340g) cheese, cut into 1/2-inch cubes (see note) Toppings (see note) Directions Combine flour, yeast, and salt in the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with a dough hook attachment. Stir to combine, then add water. Mix on low speed until dough comes together into a rough ball, then shut off mixer and let rest for 10 minutes. Continue mixing at medium-low speed until dough forms a smooth, silky ball, about 10 minutes longer. (It should stick to the bottom of the bowl as it kneads rather than riding around the edges.) Remove dough hook, form dough into a tight ball, set in the bottom of the mixer bowl, cover tightly with plastic wrap, and set aside in a warm place until dough has roughly doubled in volume, about 2 hours. Pour a couple tablespoons olive oil in the bottom of a Detroit-style anodized aluminum pan or two 8- by 8-inch cake pans. (Split dough in half if using cake pans.) Transfer dough to pan(s) and turn to coat in oil. Press down on dough and spread it toward the edges. You won’t be able to get it all the way to the edges; this is okay. Spread it as much as you can without tearing, then cover tightly in plastic and set aside for 30 minutes to allow dough to relax. Return to dough and stretch it out again. It should be able to reach the edges this time. If not, let it rest a little more and try again. To get the dough to stay in the corners, stretch it up beyond the corners so that it pulls back into place. Once dough is stretched, cover again and set aside while you make the sauce. For the Sauce: Adjust oven rack to lowest position and preheat oven to 550°F (290°C), or as close to it as your oven gets. Heat 2 tablespoons (30ml) olive oil in a medium saucepan over medium heat until shimmering. Add minced garlic, oregano, and pepper flakes and cook, stirring, until fragrant, about 30 seconds. Add tomatoes, garlic powder, onion powder, and sugar. Bring to a simmer and cook until reduced to about 3 cups, about 30 minutes. Season to taste with salt. To Form the Pizza: Press down on dough with your fingertips to remove any large air bubbles. Lay half of pepperoni (if using) evenly over face of dough. Top with cheese, spreading it evenly all the way to the very edges of the pan, then add remaining pepperoni. Spoon sauce over surface in 3 even rows. (You will need only about half the sauce—save the rest for another pizza.) Transfer to oven and bake until edges are black and bubbly and exposed cheese on top is starting to lightly brown, 12 to 15 minutes. Transfer to a trivet or folded kitchen towel on countertop. Run a thin metal spatula all the way around the edges of the pan to loosen the pizza. Carefully lift it out and slide it onto a cutting board. Cut pizza and serve. Notes &amp;amp; tips The original recipe calls for brick cheese. I’ve had trouble finding this and use a combination of low-moisture mozzarella, mild cheddar, parmesean, and asiago. My preferred toppings are caramelized onion and mushroom. For best results, use a Detroit-style anodized aluminum pan. If you can’t get your hands on that kind of pan, you can split the recipe into two square 8- by 8-inch cake pans. Resources This recipe is taken from serious eats with essentially no changes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/detroit-style-pizza.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/detroit-style-pizza.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The perfect chocolate chip cookie</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/recipes/desserts/perfect-chocolate-chip-cookie.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The perfect chocolate chip cookie" /><published>2021-10-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/recipes/desserts/perfect-chocolate-chip-cookie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/recipes/desserts/perfect-chocolate-chip-cookie.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 ounces unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 standard ice cube 5 ounces bread flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 ounces cake flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons Diamond Crystal kosher salt or 1 teaspoon table salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 ounces granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 large egg yolks,  1 large egg white&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 ounces dark brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 ounces semisweet chocolate, roughly chopped with a knife into 1/2- to 1/4-inch chunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coarse sea salt, for garnish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Melt butter in a medium saucepan over medium-high heat. Cook, gently swirling
pan constantly, until particles begin to turn golden brown and butter smells
nutty, about 5 minutes. Remove from heat and continue swirling the pan until the
butter is a rich brown, about 15 seconds longer. Transfer to a medium bowl,
whisk in ice cube, transfer to refrigerator, and allow to cool completely, about
20 minutes, whisking occasionally.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, whisk together flour, baking soda, and salt in a large bowl. Place
granulated sugar, eggs, and vanilla extract in the bowl of a stand mixer
fitted with the whisk attachment. Whisk on medium-high speed until mixture is
pale brownish-yellow and falls off the whisk in thick ribbons when lifted, about
5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fit paddle attachment onto mixer. When brown butter mixture has cooled (it
should be just starting to turn opaque again and firm around the edges), add
brown sugar and cooled brown butter to egg mixture in stand mixer. Mix on medium
speed to combine, about 15 seconds. Add flour mixture and mix on low speed until
just barely combined, with some dry flour still remaining, about 15 seconds. Add
chocolate and mix on low speed until dough comes together, about 15 seconds
longer. Transfer to an airtight container and refrigerate dough &lt;strong&gt;at least
overnight&lt;/strong&gt; and up to 3 days.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When ready to bake, adjust oven racks to upper- and lower-middle positions
and preheat oven to 350°F. Scoop out 60g balls onto a lined baking sheet.
Tear each ball in half to reveal a rougher surface, then stick them back
together with the rough sides facing outward. Transfer to oven and bake 12
minutes. Remove pan from oven and drop on stove/counter (yes, drop!). Replace
pan and continue baking until until golden brown around edges but still soft,
about 2 to 3 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remove baking sheets from oven. While cookies are still hot, sprinkle very
lightly with coarse salt and gently press salt down to embed. Let cool for 10
minutes, then transfer cookies to a wire rack to cool completely.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Repeat steps 3 through 5 for remaining cookie dough. Allow cookies to cool
completely before storing in an airtight container, plastic bag, or cookie
jar at room temperature for up to 5 days.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notes--tips&quot;&gt;Notes &amp;amp; tips&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;High quality chocolate chips are really important! I like Guittard if you can
find them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Brown the butter more than you think! I find the cookies taste best when
butter is a rich brown.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Letting the cookies rest at least 24 hours results in a much nicer
texture/bake.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recipe is largely adapted from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seriouseats.com/the-food-lab-best-chocolate-chip-cookie-recipe&quot;&gt;serious
eats&lt;/a&gt;.
They have a great discussion/exploration of how different ingredients/techniques
affect the final cookie.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Karl Kumbier</name></author><category term="desserts" /><summary type="html">Ingredients 8 ounces unsalted butter 1 standard ice cube 5 ounces bread flour 5 ounces cake flour 3/4 teaspoon baking soda 2 teaspoons Diamond Crystal kosher salt or 1 teaspoon table salt 5 ounces granulated sugar 3 large egg yolks, 1 large egg white 2 teaspoons vanilla extract 5 ounces dark brown sugar 6 ounces semisweet chocolate, roughly chopped with a knife into 1/2- to 1/4-inch chunks Coarse sea salt, for garnish Directions Melt butter in a medium saucepan over medium-high heat. Cook, gently swirling pan constantly, until particles begin to turn golden brown and butter smells nutty, about 5 minutes. Remove from heat and continue swirling the pan until the butter is a rich brown, about 15 seconds longer. Transfer to a medium bowl, whisk in ice cube, transfer to refrigerator, and allow to cool completely, about 20 minutes, whisking occasionally. Meanwhile, whisk together flour, baking soda, and salt in a large bowl. Place granulated sugar, eggs, and vanilla extract in the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with the whisk attachment. Whisk on medium-high speed until mixture is pale brownish-yellow and falls off the whisk in thick ribbons when lifted, about 5 minutes. Fit paddle attachment onto mixer. When brown butter mixture has cooled (it should be just starting to turn opaque again and firm around the edges), add brown sugar and cooled brown butter to egg mixture in stand mixer. Mix on medium speed to combine, about 15 seconds. Add flour mixture and mix on low speed until just barely combined, with some dry flour still remaining, about 15 seconds. Add chocolate and mix on low speed until dough comes together, about 15 seconds longer. Transfer to an airtight container and refrigerate dough at least overnight and up to 3 days. When ready to bake, adjust oven racks to upper- and lower-middle positions and preheat oven to 350°F. Scoop out 60g balls onto a lined baking sheet. Tear each ball in half to reveal a rougher surface, then stick them back together with the rough sides facing outward. Transfer to oven and bake 12 minutes. Remove pan from oven and drop on stove/counter (yes, drop!). Replace pan and continue baking until until golden brown around edges but still soft, about 2 to 3 minutes. Remove baking sheets from oven. While cookies are still hot, sprinkle very lightly with coarse salt and gently press salt down to embed. Let cool for 10 minutes, then transfer cookies to a wire rack to cool completely. Repeat steps 3 through 5 for remaining cookie dough. Allow cookies to cool completely before storing in an airtight container, plastic bag, or cookie jar at room temperature for up to 5 days. Notes &amp;amp; tips High quality chocolate chips are really important! I like Guittard if you can find them. Brown the butter more than you think! I find the cookies taste best when butter is a rich brown. Letting the cookies rest at least 24 hours results in a much nicer texture/bake. Resources This recipe is largely adapted from serious eats. They have a great discussion/exploration of how different ingredients/techniques affect the final cookie.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/perfect-chocolate-chip-cookie.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/perfect-chocolate-chip-cookie.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>